Her song will not be silenced.
The Nightingale is a drama, thriller, western film directed by Jennifer Kent.
In 1825, Clare, a 21-year-old Irish convict, chases a British soldier through the rugged Tasmanian
wilderness, bent on revenge for a terrible act of violence he committed against her family.
She enlists the services of an Aboriginal tracker who is also
marked by trauma from his own violence-filled past.
Clare, played by Aisling Franciosi.
Hawkins, played by Sam Claflin.
Billy, played by Baykali Ganambarr.
Ruse, played by Damon Herriman.
Jago, played by Harry Greenwood.
Goodwin, played by Ewen Leslie.
The Nightingale is a 2018 Australian historical psychological
thriller film written and directed by Jennifer Kent.
The film stars Aisling Franciosi, Sam Claflin, Baykali Ganambarr, Damon Herriman, Harry
Greenwood, Ewen Leslie, Charlie Shotwell, Michael Sheasby, and Magnolia Maymuru.
Set in 1825 in Van Diemen's Land, it follows a young Irish convict (Franciosi) seeking vengeance against members of
the Colonial forces of Tasmania who gang-raped her and killed both her husband and infant daughter.
She is aided by an Aboriginal Tasmanian tracker (Ganambarr), who seeks
vengeance for the British occupiers' Black War against his people.
The Nightingale premiered at the 75th Venice International Film Festival on 6 September 2018, where it was nominated
for the Golden Lion and won the Special Jury Prize, while Ganambarr won the Marcello Mastroianni Award.
The film was theatrically released in Australia on 29 August 2019 and was a box office
failure, grossing only $988,687 against its $2 million production budget.
Despite generating controversy for its graphic portrayal of rape and murder, it received critical acclaim, with particular
praise for Kent's direction, the performances of the cast, and acknowledgement of racial violence in Australia.
It is the first film to include palawa kani, a reconstructed
form of the once extinct Tasmanian languages.
The Nightingale received a leading 15 nominations at the 9th AACTA Awards, winning 6, including Best Film, Best Direction and
Best Screenplay, Original or Adapted for Kent, Best Actress for Franciosi, and Best Supporting Actress for Maymuru.
The film explores themes of australia, rape, revenge, murder, brutality.
The tone is intense and dark and emotional.